<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The GUTS&#43; System</title>
    <link>http://gutsplus.tk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The GUTS&#43; System</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 15:25:30 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gutsplus.tk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Player&#39;s Handbook</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/rules/players-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/rules/players-handbook/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the wonderful world of GUTS, where players and game masters work together to progress the story within the game world.
The name &amp;ldquo;GUTS+&amp;rdquo; is an acronym for the base character stats in the game: &amp;ldquo;G&amp;rdquo;umption, &amp;ldquo;U&amp;rdquo;tility, &amp;ldquo;T&amp;rdquo;hought, and &amp;ldquo;S&amp;rdquo;lyness, &amp;ldquo;plus&amp;rdquo; additional custom stats that each player chooses to round out their character.
Gameplay is heavily narrative-based and relies on a Game Master who is comfortable either improvising frequently to give players the smoothest narrative experience possible or railroading their players into following a specific path for the sake of keeping the story solid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Character Creation</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/rules/players-handbook/character-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/rules/players-handbook/character-creation/</guid>
      <description>Your character is your avatar in the game world, and it&amp;rsquo;s also what makes playing the game fun and interesting! When you create your character, it&amp;rsquo;s important to try to build them based on how the character would actually be within the world&amp;hellip; you&amp;rsquo;ll see what I mean.
First, get your Character Sheet so you can fill it out with your character information.
Biography
To create your character, first you need a backstory, a personality, and an appearance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing the Game</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/rules/players-handbook/playing-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/rules/players-handbook/playing-the-game/</guid>
      <description>Playing the GUTS+ System requires only the occasional D6 roll and a bit of imagination.
The Basics
Role playing is a bit like collaborating with a group to tell a story with special rules in place that prevent the story from going too far off the rails. The GM sets up the world and the situation, and it&amp;rsquo;s up to you and your fellow players to work through that situation together using your characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Master&#39;s Handbook</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/rules/game-masters-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/rules/game-masters-handbook/</guid>
      <description>This guide will walk you through the concepts of how the game world works and what your role as the Game Master entails. As Game Master (GM), your role is architect, narrator, decider, intermediary, friend, enemy, and anything else that is required for the players to navigate the game world. It&amp;rsquo;s a big responsibility, but it&amp;rsquo;s also a lot of fun!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grimoire</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/rules/grimoire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/rules/grimoire/</guid>
      <description>This is a guide to the Magic system in GUTS+.
Magic in GUTS+ depends entirely on the concept of Essence. Every living creature is able to utilize their Essence, but it requires a great amount of focus and control to use it. So long as you have an ability that can harness their Essence, you can manipulate it to do a variety of interesting things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essence</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/rules/grimoire/essence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/rules/grimoire/essence/</guid>
      <description>Every living thing has a soul, or &amp;ldquo;Essence,&amp;rdquo; that is tightly connected to their body. It is completely invisible but absolutely there, but few people know about it because its bounds are your own body&amp;rsquo;s bounds. The Essence is what fills the spaces between your cells and makes you feel alive. There are a number of different makeups of Essense, some more dense or hotter or colder than others, but all Essense is composed of the same, tangible substance that is interwoven into the very being of its owner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mother Earth</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/campaigns/mother-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 15:25:30 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/campaigns/mother-earth/</guid>
      <description>Startere was a sleepy, “all-American” town situated in the middle of Nowhere. For years, there were no paved roads into or out of the town, and there was just desert all around–temperate desert, but a wasteland all the same. In recent years, however, people wanting to escape the city life have come and developed suburbs along the outskirts of town, charmed by the quaint little town.
Along the main road, there’s the old general store, mostly stocked with local woodwork from tables and chairs to toys though it sometimes has some factory-made things when a rare shipment comes in; there’s the farm stalls once a week where everyone trades the fruits (and vegetables and eggs and other farm things) of their labor; and a bunch of other useful things like the tailor, a diner, and the big, elaborate Town Hall building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session 1</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/sessions/mother-earth_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 15:24:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/sessions/mother-earth_0/</guid>
      <description>GM:
A crowd converges on the old town hall, where the mayor has called a meeting to discuss the strange happenings in the sky for the past few weeks. There is no more sitting room, but all of the windows and doors have been opened, and a speaker system has been set up on the stage where the mayor will be speaking. After a bit of time, the mayor, a very small man named Fred Devonshire with a pristine, periwinkle suit and a perfectly waxed, white moustache, climbs onto a stool to be seen at the podium at the front of the town hall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/posts/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 10:28:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/posts/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the home of the GUTS+ System, a role-playing game system for everyone! The system itself is still in development, but I believe it is far enough along to actually begin using for your gameplay.
As you have probably read on the home page, the basics of how to play are available for free, but the gist of the system is this: your characters themselves define what they are able to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clothing</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/items/clothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/items/clothing/</guid>
      <description>Clothing is a subset of items that can be worn on a character&amp;rsquo;s torso, legs, or feet. When they are not being worn, they are treated as regular items stored in the character&amp;rsquo;s inventory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Definition of Game Master</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/definition/game-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/definition/game-master/</guid>
      <description>The Game Master (GM for short) is the narrator and controller of the game world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Definition of In-Character</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/definition/in-character/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/definition/in-character/</guid>
      <description>Actions taken by a character rather than the player.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Definition of Non-Playable Character</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/definition/non-playable-character/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/definition/non-playable-character/</guid>
      <description>A character played and controlled by the Game Master instead of by the players.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Definition of Out-of-Character</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/definition/out-of-character/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/definition/out-of-character/</guid>
      <description>Actions and dialog taken by the player but not the character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Definition of nDs</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/definition/nds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/definition/nds/</guid>
      <description>The formula representing how many of what type of die to roll (n dice with s sides). For example, 2D6 means a roll of 2 six-sided dice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gus</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/characters/mother-earth_gus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/characters/mother-earth_gus/</guid>
      <description>Appearance Male, 19 years old, caucasian. Has chin-length, curly black hair, round, dark, close-set eyes, a small, pointed nose that curves up, and thin, perpetually chapped lips on an perfectly round face. He is about 5′ 5″ and weighs 145 lbs, and he walks in a half-lumbering, half-slithering way. Rarely wears anything other than graphic tees, sweat pants, and tennis shoes.
Background Gus has been interested in computers his whole life, and has worked on many unfinished projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gus&#39;s Equipment for Mother Earth Session 1</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/equipment/mother-earth_gus_0_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/equipment/mother-earth_gus_0_0/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gus&#39;s Equipment for Mother Earth Session 1</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/inventories/mother-earth_gus_0_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/inventories/mother-earth_gus_0_0/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gus&#39;s Injuries for Mother Earth Session 1</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/injuries/mother-earth_gus_0_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/injuries/mother-earth_gus_0_0/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gus&#39;s Stats for Mother Earth Session 1</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/stats/mother-earth_gus_0_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/stats/mother-earth_gus_0_0/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jeans</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/items/clothing/jeans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/items/clothing/jeans/</guid>
      <description>A basic legs clothing item. Can be styled however a player would like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kami</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/characters/mother-earth_kami/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/characters/mother-earth_kami/</guid>
      <description>Appearance Female, 18 years old, east Asian. Has chin-length, straight, black hair, narrow, dark eyes, a small, pointed nose, and full lips on an round, somewhat flat face with a pointed chin. She is about 5′ 4″ and weighs 120 lbs. She walks confidently and gracefully.
Background Kami is the daughter of wealthy businesswomen who are co-owners and CEOs of the megacorporation that has been behind the growth of Startere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kami&#39;s Equipment for Mother Earth Session 1</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/equipment/mother-earth_kami_0_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/equipment/mother-earth_kami_0_0/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kami&#39;s Equipment for Mother Earth Session 1</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/inventories/mother-earth_kami_0_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/inventories/mother-earth_kami_0_0/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kami&#39;s Injuries for Mother Earth Session 1</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/injuries/mother-earth_kami_0_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/injuries/mother-earth_kami_0_0/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kami&#39;s Stats for Mother Earth Session 1</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/stats/mother-earth_kami_0_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/stats/mother-earth_kami_0_0/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monsters</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/bestiary/monsters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/bestiary/monsters/</guid>
      <description>Monsters are typically non-human creatures that are hostile toward player characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanette</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/characters/mother-earth_nanette/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/characters/mother-earth_nanette/</guid>
      <description>Appearance Female, 16 years old, Israeli. Has shoulder-length, light brown hair, large, hazel eyes, a large, round nose, and thin lips on an almost pear-shaped face, a tall, gangly frame, and an unsure gait. About 5′ 9″ and somewhere around 130 lbs. The very image of a library nerd girl.
Background Nanette grew up very sheltered. Always homeschooled, she has not had much contact with people outside of her family, but at the age of 16, she feels that she has missed out on life and wants to befriend people outside of her comfort zone and expand her tiny world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanette&#39;s Equipment for Mother Earth Session 1</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/equipment/mother-earth_nanette_0_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/equipment/mother-earth_nanette_0_0/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanette&#39;s Equipment for Mother Earth Session 1</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/inventories/mother-earth_nanette_0_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/inventories/mother-earth_nanette_0_0/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanette&#39;s Injuries for Mother Earth Session 1</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/injuries/mother-earth_nanette_0_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/injuries/mother-earth_nanette_0_0/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanette&#39;s Stats for Mother Earth Session 1</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/stats/mother-earth_nanette_0_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/stats/mother-earth_nanette_0_0/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slime</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/bestiary/monsters/slime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/bestiary/monsters/slime/</guid>
      <description>Appearance A slimy blob that can range in size anywhere from 1&amp;frasl;2 to 2 square meters and can be just about any color of the rainbow.
Background Slimes are created from magical fallout that results in lost or disconnected essence congealing around a fluid of some kind.
Personality Slimes are semi-sentient and spend most of their time sitting around until another living creature approaches it. At the opportune time, they will attempt to jump at and surround their target, at which point, they will begin to kill the host and intercept its essence, allowing itself to grow larger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sneakers</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/items/clothing/sneakers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/items/clothing/sneakers/</guid>
      <description>A basic feet clothing item. Can be styled however a player would like.
Allows character to comfortably walk on hard or uneven ground.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T-Shirt</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/items/clothing/t-shirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/items/clothing/t-shirt/</guid>
      <description>A basic torso clothing item. Can be styled however a player would like.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>