<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Characters on The GUTS&#43; System</title>
    <link>http://gutsplus.tk/characters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Characters on The GUTS&#43; System</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gutsplus.tk/characters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gus</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/characters/mother-earth_gus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/characters/mother-earth_gus/</guid>
      <description>Appearance Male, 19 years old, caucasian. Has chin-length, curly black hair, round, dark, close-set eyes, a small, pointed nose that curves up, and thin, perpetually chapped lips on an perfectly round face. He is about 5′ 5″ and weighs 145 lbs, and he walks in a half-lumbering, half-slithering way. Rarely wears anything other than graphic tees, sweat pants, and tennis shoes.
Background Gus has been interested in computers his whole life, and has worked on many unfinished projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kami</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/characters/mother-earth_kami/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/characters/mother-earth_kami/</guid>
      <description>Appearance Female, 18 years old, east Asian. Has chin-length, straight, black hair, narrow, dark eyes, a small, pointed nose, and full lips on an round, somewhat flat face with a pointed chin. She is about 5′ 4″ and weighs 120 lbs. She walks confidently and gracefully.
Background Kami is the daughter of wealthy businesswomen who are co-owners and CEOs of the megacorporation that has been behind the growth of Startere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanette</title>
      <link>http://gutsplus.tk/characters/mother-earth_nanette/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gutsplus.tk/characters/mother-earth_nanette/</guid>
      <description>Appearance Female, 16 years old, Israeli. Has shoulder-length, light brown hair, large, hazel eyes, a large, round nose, and thin lips on an almost pear-shaped face, a tall, gangly frame, and an unsure gait. About 5′ 9″ and somewhere around 130 lbs. The very image of a library nerd girl.
Background Nanette grew up very sheltered. Always homeschooled, she has not had much contact with people outside of her family, but at the age of 16, she feels that she has missed out on life and wants to befriend people outside of her comfort zone and expand her tiny world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>